Patience, Mister Kent, patience.
耐心点, Kent 先生, 耐心点
Astrid should have been in contact by now.
Astrid 现在应该已经联系我们了
Can't you contact her?
你不能联系她吗？
If I knew where she was.
我得知道她在哪里才行
Oh no, I know she's in the Central European Zone,
but that's a big place.
哦, 不, 我知道她在中欧区, 但那个地方很大
No, we'll just have to sweat it out and wait.
不行, 我们只能焦急地等着了
Astrid, you're back. Switch to scramble.
Astrid, 你回来了．切到fixme吧
Scramble? Are we being monitored?
fixme? 我们被监视了？
- (It's possible)
- Right. Switching now.
好, 现在切过去
Denes dead?
Denes 死了？
Yes, shot in the back.
是的, 后背中枪了
Well, it looks as if our friend Salamander's
had a field day, doesn't it?
那, 看来好像我们的朋友 Salamander 忙了一整天了, 是吧？
I'm afraid I haven't done very well.
恐怕我没能做得很好
Don't worry. It's not your fault.
Look, stay put and we'll join you.
别担心, 不是你的错．这样, 安静等着, 我们来找你
The girl Astrid Ferrier, she was in the Central European Zone.
这个女孩儿 Astrid Ferrier, 她之前在中欧区
Was she? Well she's here now. Have you found her?
是吗？那她现在在这里．你找到她了吗？
I think so. One of my men saw someone
answering her description...
我想是．我一个手下看到一个人跟这个描述相符...
...going into Giles Kent's office earlier.
...她走进了 Giles Kent 的办公室
Was she alone?
她一个人吗？
Yes, sir. But shortly after someone else followed her in.
是的, 长官． 但随后另外一个人跟着她进去了
Well who, man, who?
哦, 谁, 伙计, 是谁？
Leader Salamander's food taster sir, Fariah.
领袖 Salamander 的食物品尝员 Fariah
Fariah?
是 Fariah?
But what are they going to do to Jamie and Victoria?
但他们会把 Jamie 和 Victoria 怎么样？
I don't know.
我不知道
Hold them in the Central European zone
until Salamander has time to deal with them.
把他们关在中欧区, 等 Salamander 有时间时来处理他们
No. You're wrong. Salamander doesn't care for loose ends.
不, 你错了．Salamander 不关心这些fixme
He brought them back with him.
他把他们带回去了
What, to his headquarters, the Research Centre?
什么？带回他的总部, 研究中心了？
Yes. He's going to try to get information from them.
是的, 他打算从他们那里问出点东西来
How far will he go to get it?
他为了得到信息会到什么地步？
Very far.
不择手段
Oh, that's very comforting.
哦, 那还真让人放心
I tell you I know Salamander.
我跟你说, 我了解 Salamander
Yes, I... I'm not quite clear about your part in all this. /57.9
是的, 我...我不清楚你在这里是个什么角色？
You work for Salamander, suddenly you fall over
yourselves to betray him.
你为 Salamander 工作, 突然间你掉转身子背叛了他
I came here for that purpose, yes.
我来这里就是为了那个目的, 是的
Why?
为什么？
Because I have every reason to hate Salamander. /08.5
因为我有太多理由恨 Salamander
He blackmailed me into being his personal servant. /11.5
他要挟我做他个人的仆人
I even had to smile when he told me to.
他告诉我的时候我还不得不微笑
What sort of blackmail? What had you done?
什么样的要挟？你做了什么？
Does it really matter?
真的有关系吗？
Oh, no no no of course not my dear.
Well nobody's perfect, Kent./22.0
噢, 不不不, 当然没关系, 我亲爱的．没有人是完美的, Kent
But I... I still can't help wondering why...
但我...我还是忍不住好奇为什么...
...why I hadn't tried to expose Salamander?
...为什么我没有试过揭发 Salamander?
Well you were in a unique position to do so.
对, 你位置特殊适合这么做
Because without any proof I'd be wasting my time.
因为没有任何证据的话, 我就只会浪费自己的时间
Proof! Proof! Proof! It always comes back to the same thing. /35.4
证据！证据！证据！总是会回到同一个东西
No one has any evidence against Salamander!
没有人有 Salamander 的任何证据!
We have some.
我们有一些
Not enough! It's not enough! Salamander covers up too well.
不够！远不够！Salamander 伪装得太好了
I have what you want.
我有你想要的东西
But I thought that you said...
但我记得你说...
No. Not about me. Fedorin.
不．不是我的．Fedorin
Fedorin? A public embezzler who commits suicide?
Fedorin? 一个自杀的贪污犯？
Salamander engineered nearly every one of those swindles,
and I can prove it.
Salamander 构造了几乎每一场诈骗, 我可以证明
How?
怎么证明？
Fedorin's file.
Fedorin 的文件
Is the building surrounded?
整栋楼都被包围了吗？
A-three's in position, Captain.
fixme
Just closing up the gaps.
开始收网吧
Well you haven't brought me here on a fool's errand, I hope?
But I'm afraid this... this still isn't evidence,
it's... it's not real evidence.
但我担心这个...这个仍然不是证据, 这个...不是真正的证据
You mean even this doesn't convince you about Salamander?
你的意思是这个仍然不能说服你对 Salamander 的看法？
Oh, I'm not saying that.
哦, 我不是这个意思
Well then you'll do it? You'll impersonate him?
怎样, 你肯干吗？你会假冒他吗？
And of course when they see you with me
they're bound to think you're Salamander.
而且当他们看见你跟我在一起, 他们肯定会相信你就是Salamander
But I... I still don't know if I can carry it off.
但我...我还是不知道我能否瞒得过去
It's the only way to get your friends released.
这是让你的朋友得救的唯一方法
Yesss...
是的...
Of course, there are...
当然了, 有一些...
Oh I see, yes of course, there are conditions, aren't there? /36.0
哦我明白, 当然了, 有一些条件, 是吧？
You help me, I defeat Salamander?
你帮助我, 而我击垮 Salamander?
Now look, you're giving me the biggest opportunity
I'll ever have of ridding the world of this monster./42.5
看看, 你给了我最大的机会, 让我能在这个怪物的世界里驰骋fixme
Either I can convince you one way,
or I'll have to do it another.
要么我可以说服你, 要么我就得另外想办法
What you really want me to do is to kill him, isn't it?
你真正想让我做的, 是杀了他, 是不是？
What else do you do when someone is evil?
如果有个人很邪恶, 你还想怎么做？
Private justice, eh? Oh no, no. /54.0
私性正义, 嗯？噢, 不, 不行
I'll expose him, ruin him, have him arrested,
but I won't be his executioner. /58.1
我会揭发他, 毁他名声, 让他被逮捕, 但我不会成为他的行刑者
No one has that right.
没人有那个权利
Sometimes it's necessary.
有时这是必须的
- No.  - Yes, Doctor yes!
- 不  - 是, 博士, 是！
Right, we'll move in.
好了, 我们进去吧
Either you get rid of Salamander,
or we won't lift a finger to help your friends.
要么你干掉 Salamander , 要么我们一根手指也不会帮你救你的朋友
Mister Kent, look.
Kent 先生, 看
I'd make up my mind quickly if I were you.
如果我是你的话, 我会快速做出决定
- Why?  - Have a look out of the window.
- 为什么？  - 看一眼窗外面
Well, what is it?
啊, 那是什么？
What do we do now?
我们现在做什么？
Over here, quick!
在这边, 快点！
Well what's that?
好, 那是什么？
- Through here, the ventilator shaft.
- The files.
- 走这边, 通风井  - 文件
- Come on, quick.  - But where did it go?
- 跟上, 快点  - 但它去哪儿了？
It doesn't matter, come on.
没有关系, 快点
It's locked.
被锁住了
Now you, Doctor, next.
该你了, 博士, 下一个
- Oh what about you?
- Kent! Open the door
- 哦你怎么样？  - Kent! 把门打开
Oh no, you're too important. You go, and Giles.
噢不, 你太重要了．你去, 还有 Giles
- I'll follow  - All right.
- 我随后  - 好吧
Very well...
很好...
...you leave me no alternative. Break it down.
...你让我没有选择了．破开它
Get back!
退后!
Get away from that door!
离门远一点！
Did you get the others?
你找到其他人了吗？
Not yet, sir.
还没有, 长官
Now listen to me. It was you, Astrid Ferrier,
Giles Kent and another.
现在听我说．这里有你, Astrid Ferrier, Giles Kent 和另外一个人
Who was the other man?
那个人是谁？
You'll know soon... soon enough.
你很快就会知道...非常快
I want to know now.
我现在就想知道
Sir...
长官...
Shut up! Well?
闭嘴！怎样？
You can't threaten me now, Benik.
I can only die once. And someone's beaten you to it.
现在你威胁不了我了, Benik．我只会死一次, 有人为此会揍你的fixme
Who was the other man?
另外那个人是谁？
Sir?
长官？
She's dead.
她死了
Good.
好
Fedorin's file. Thank you.
Fedorin 的档案, 谢谢你
What you mean is you failed.
你的意思是你失败了
I always said something should be done about Kent.
我一直都说应该对 Kent 动手
You always say. You say things, but you don't think.
你一直在说．你是在说, 但你不思考
You exceeded your authority, Benik. A woman's been killed.
你超出对你的授权了, Benik．一个女人被杀了
Resisting arrest.
她拘捕
Maybe. But you can't just take the law into your own hands.
也许吧．但你没法把法律掌握在自己手上
Giles Kent hadn't broken any rules that I know of.
Giles Kent 据我所知没有破坏任何规则
For sure he'd show himself one day,
he was simply building up his resistance group.
他肯定会在某天露面的, 他只是在组建他的抵抗小组
Resistance group! The man's a traitor.
These people are rebels./35.0
抵抗小组！责任是个卖国贼, 这些人都是叛军
Bruce, you must find this man who impersonated me.
The dangers are obvious. /41.3
Bruce, 你必须找到这个冒充我的人．危险性是显然的
He could walk in anywhere at any time
pretending to be me and ruin everything.
他可能在任何时间任何地点假冒我, 把一切都毁了
You can leave that to me.
这你就交给我吧
How so?
怎么会这样？
Benik, come with me and I'll go over
the security arrangements with you now.
Benik, 跟我来, 我现在跟你过一遍安保措施
Do as you're told!
遵守命令！
I think you'll find this interesting.
我想你会发现这个很有意思
What? The girl Fariah had this? What can I say?
什么？Fariah 那个女孩儿有这个？我能说什么？
Yes sir?
什么事, 长官？
The records room is out of bounds. I am not to be disturbed. /28.3
fixme 不要来打扰我
See that the security locks are engaged.
确保安全锁已经锁上了
Very well, sir. For how long, sir?
好的, 长官．锁多久, 长官？
For as long as I say so.
我说多久就多久
Yes sir.
好的, 长官
It seems that Salamander's locked himself away
and can't be got at.
看起来 Salamander 把他自己锁起来了, 找不到了 fixme
So?
那?
Well, suppose the place caught fire?
哦, 加入这个地方着火了呢？
It won't.
不会的
Don't be foolish!
被犯傻！
Look, I can only tell you that when Salamander works in records,
听着, Salamander 在fixme, 他时不时这样
as he does from time to time, no one is allowed in.
我只能告诉你, 这个时候不允许任何人进去
I can understand if it were a... er... a... laboratory
or... a... research room of some sort, but a... /45.2
要是这是一间...实验室或者...某种研究室, 我还能理解, 但是....
a records room? What sort of records have you got in there anyway?
一间fixme? 你们那里面有什么样的fixme?
What did you want to see him about?
你想见他做什么？
Never mind. I just don't like mysteries. /52.9
没什么, 我只是不喜欢这么神秘
Salamander's far too important to lock himself away like this,
Salamander 太重要了, 不能这样把自己锁起来
anything might happen, a world emergency. /59.2
一旦发生点什么, 都是世界级事件
Suppose I had to order you to let me in there?
如果我不得不命令你让我进去呢？
It wouldn't do any good. When the locks are switched over
they can only be opened from the inside.
那也没什么用, 一旦锁上了, 就只能从里面打开
I have returned. Take radiation precautions.
I will make a report about the surface.
我回来了．小心辐射危险．我要准备一份关于地表的报告
He's back!
他回来了！
He's managed to get back again.
他历尽艰险又回来了fixme
Let's hope he's got some good news this time.
期望这次他能带来些好消息
Do you think Salamander's found some more food, Swann?
你觉得 Salamander 找到了更多食物吗, Swann?
I hope so, otherwise we're finished.
Where's that stock list?
我期望是, 否则我们就完了．那张储物清单呢？
Welcome back, Salamander. Are you all right?
欢迎回来, Salamander ．你没事把？
Don't, don't come too near my friend,
I am not yet decontaminated.
别, 别靠太近我的朋友．我还没消毒
I am too weary, totally weary.
我很疲惫, 完全累坏了
You shouldn't have made this trip, Salamander,
you're doing too much.
你不应该来这一趟的, Salamander．你付出得太多了
Someone has to bring back the food for you, my friend, huh? /41.3
必须得有个人给你们带食物回来, 我的朋友, 是吧？
You know that the radiation is slowly killing me, don't you Swann?
你知道吗, 辐射正在慢慢地杀死我, 是不, Swann?
You're just doing too much.
你付出得太多了
I worry about you all the time. What're you going to do
when I am no longer here?
我一直都担心你们．如果我不再出现在这里了你们该怎么办？
Radiation gets a little more each time, hm?
One day, that needle will stay at maximum radiation.
辐射一次比一次强了, 嗯？某一天那根针会一直指向最大辐射强度
Don't say that.
别那么说
Why Mary. Colin. Huh, it's my big joke, huh?
为什么？ Mary, Colin． 哈, 这是个大玩笑, 哈？
Just to frighten you a little.
只是为了吓唬你们一下
I've got good news for us!
我有消息带给大家！
We can return to the surface?
我们可以回到地面上去了？
No no no not yet, but I've found another store of food...
不不不, 还不行, 但我找到了另外一个食物储藏点...
Thank goodness!
感谢老天！
...it is undamaged. Colin, open the last store of wine, huh?
...保存完好．Colin, 打开最后那批酒吧, 哈?
Go on, you help him too, Mary.
去吧, 你也帮帮他 Mary
You must take it slowly for goodness sake.
你必须慢点, 老天
I'm all right my friend. I'm just a little dizzy. It's... /41.0
我没事, 我的朋友．我只是有点头晕．这...
It's terrible up there, you know, Swann, you've no idea. /48.0
上面情况很糟糕, 你知道吗, Swann, 你都想不到
Right, I am ready.
好了, 我准备好了
But I still don't understand what's happened to Fariah.
但我还是没搞懂 Fariah 发生了什么
She went the wrong way. We lost her.
她走错路了, 我们失去她了
Well we must find her!
You don't seem to realize how vital it is.
那我们必须找到她！你似乎没有意识到这有多关键
Doctor, hold still a moment will you?
博士, 把住一会儿, 好吗？
Sorry.
抱歉
There. Look at that, Giles, isn't it amazing?
那里．看那个, Giles, 是不是很惊人？
Salamander to the life.
fixme
Yes, it's... it's not bad.
是的, 这个...这不错
Shh, I think I heard something.
嘘, 我觉得我听到了什么
Well perhaps it's Fariah.
哦可能是 Fariah
Stay where you are. I've been looking forward
to meeting you again.
呆着别动．我一直期待着再次见到你